MICHAEL MELLO PAPERS (APAP287) 1800-2008
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Michael Mello Papers1800-20081970-2004
nam_apap287
Michael A. Mello (1957-2008) was an internationally recognized authority on the death penalty and capital punishment issues. He was a lawyer, professor, and author. Michael Mello served as counsel or informal advisor to many significant cases, including Joseph Robert Crazy Joe Spaziano, Theodore Kaczynski, Theodore Bundy, Rolando Cruz, Alvin Ford, Stephen Todd Booker, and Robert Straight.
Mello, Michael
42.2
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Biographical History
Michael A. Mello (1957-2008) was an internationally recognized authority on the death penalty and capital punishment issues. He graduated from the University of Virginia, School of Law in 1982. From 1982-1983, he worked as a law clerk for Judge Robert S. Vance of the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh District where his principal responsibility included working on many of the capital cases for which the judge was assigned. From 1983-1985, he worked as an assistant public defender for the Capital Appeals Division of the Office of the Flordia Public Defender where he was lead cousel in three capital cases and active co-counsel in ten others as well as providing tactical and strategic assistance to pro bono attorneys, developing systemic strategies, lobbying, and testifying before the Florida Legislature. From 1985-1986, Mello worked for the Office of the Capital Collateral Representative for the State of Florida, a first-of-its-kind state agency charged with representing all indigient inmantes on Florida's death row whose sentences had been affirmed by the Florida Supreme Court and who had been denied executive clemency by the governor. Though he left his position at the Capital Collateral Respresentative in 1986, he remained on friendly terms with the organization where he provided advice and took the occasional case until 1995 when he cut off ties with the organization. From 1988 until his death in November 2008, Michael Mello was a professor of law at Vermont Law School where he taught courses on criminal law, constitutional criminal procedure, the legal profession, and a capital punishment seminar.
Michael Mello served as counsel or informal advisor to many significant cases, including Joseph Robert Crazy Joe Spaziano, Theodore Kaczynski, Theodore Bundy, Rolando Cruz, Alvin Ford, Stephen Todd Booker, and Robert Straight. He also served as counsel for the American Bar Association, National Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers, National Legal Aid and Defender Association, American Jewish Congress, American Jewish Committee, and others.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes material related to some of Michael Mello's more significant cases; including Joseph Crazy Joe Spaziano, Davidson James, Bennie Demps, and Nollie Lee Martin. Also included are drafts and complete copies of a number of Michael Mellos publications, research files used by Michael Mello in the various aspects of his professional life, case files for which Michael Mello may have been involved in some capacity. The majority of the material involves Michael Mello's professional life from the mid-1980s to the late 1990s.
Researchers should note that materials related to some of Michael Mello's most significant cases such as Theodore Bundy and Theodore Kaczynski is not included in this collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into eight topical series.
Acquisition Information
Michael Mello and his wife Deanna donated these records to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in a series of three acquisitions in 2006, 2012, and 2013. 2006-2013
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Selected Bibliography
Michael Mello, Legalizing Gay Marriage 2004
Michael Mello, Deathwork: Defending the Condemned 2002
Michael Mello, The Wrong Man: A True Story of Innocence and Death Row 2001
Michael Mello, The United States of American Versus Theodore John Kaczynski: Ethics, Power and the Invention of the Unabomber 1999
Michael Mello, Dead Wrong: A Death Row Lawyer Speaks Out Against Capital Punishment 1997
Michael Mello, Against the Death Penalty: The Relentless Dissents of Justices Brennan and Marshall 1996
Michael Mello, Representing the Unabomber, in LEGAL ETHICS STORIES 2005
Michael Mello, Facing Death Alone, in INTERNATIONAL LIBRARY OF ESSAYS ON LAW AND SOCIETY: CAPITAL PUNISHMENT 2005
Michael Mello and Paul Perkins, Closing the Circle: The Illusion of Counsel in Capital Cases, in AMERICAS EXPERIMENT WITH CAPITAL PUNISHMENT 1998
Michael Mello, Another Attorney for Life, in FACING THE DEATH PENALTY: ESSAYS ON A CRUEL AND UNUSUAL PUNISHMENT 1989
Michael Mello, Facing Death Alone, in A CAPITAL PUNISHMENT ANTHOLOGY 1993
Subject and Genre Headings
Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Death Penalty; Mello, Michael; Spaziano, Joseph; James, Davidson; Martin, Nollie Lee; Demps, Bennie; Death row inmates--Florida; Capital punishment--United States; Capital punishment--Florida; Legal research and writing; Death Penalty; Capital punishment--United States--Cases; Executions (Law)--United States--Cases; Capital punishment--Moral and ethical aspects; Legislative acts; Legal documents; Decisions; Drafts (documents); Correspondence; Manuscripts (document genre); Case files; Books
Container List
- Joseph Spaziano, 1932-2008; 1; 7.6
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains materials related to the various trials of Joseph Spaziano and represents material created or used by Michael Mello in Joseph Spazianos defense or during the writing of Michael Mellos book The Wrong Man: A True Story of Innocence and the Death Row; included in this series are legal materials, correspondence, notes, and research materials.
  - Research Materials Hypnosis Articles, 1932-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research Material- Criminal Justice Act of 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Research Materials- Scope of Gardner Issue, 1958; 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Research Materials- Jury Override (1 of 2), 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Research Materials- Jury Override (2 of 2), 1966 -1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Research Materials- Hypnosis Cases, 1968; 1971; 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Research Materials- Per Se Exclusion, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Interview- Anthony Frank Dilisio, 1975 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - 9th Circuit FL, Trial Proceedings Volume II, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Research Material- Alford v. State, 1975; 1977; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chronological Testimony of Athony Frank Dilisio, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (1 of 9), 1975- 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Must consult archivist to view material
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (2 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (3 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (4 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (5 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (6 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (7 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (8 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - UCI Inmate Records, [Restricted] (9 of 9), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - UCI Medical File, [Restricted] (1 of 2), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - UCI Medical File, [Restricted] (2 of 2), 1975-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. I, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. II, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. III, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - upreme Court of Florida- Vol. IV, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. V, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. VI, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida- Vol. VII, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida (1 of 3), 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida (2 of 3), 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of Florida (3 of 3), 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Research Materials, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Unknown Argument, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Research Material, Allen Charge, 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reference Material, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Research Materials- Gerald Eugene Stano, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 18th Century, FL- Imposition of Sentence after Remand, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Presentation Investigaton, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of FL. - Record on Resentencing Vol. I, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court of FL. - Record on Resentencing Vol. II, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - News Reports, 1981; 1984-1986; 1989-1991; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Spaziano Cases in Southern Reporter, 1983; 1986; 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - U.S SC (1 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - U.S SC (2 of 2), 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gardner Resentencing - Diskette, 1981-1984; Undated (Oversized 1, Item 4)
  - Gardener Resentencing, 1981-1984; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Research Materials, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Research Materials, Habeas Corpus, 1982; 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Research Material, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clemency- Investigative Materials, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Reference Materials, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1984-1985; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- In Support of Executive Clemency, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- In Support, Appendix, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- Supplemental Memorandum, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency in RE: Joseph R. Spaziano- Supplemental Memorandum In Support of Executive Clemency, Appendix, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL. (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL. (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL., Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL., Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, Appendix Vol. I of III, (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- 18th Circuit, FL., Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, Appendix Vol. I of III, (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Florida v. Spaziano- Eighteenth Circuit- Rule 3.850- Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence, Appendix II, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 9th Circuit FL, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal, Vol. II, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Appeal, Vol. I, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL. SC, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - U.S. D.C. FL., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Research Materials, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - FLSC- Record on Appeal, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - USDL, FL, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Spaziano Federal Habeas- Index of Claims - Computer Contents, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Research Materials, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newsclippings, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal (2 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal (1 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Research Materials, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Supreme Court FL., 1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Research Material, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Record on Appeal, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Spaziano v. Wainwright - U.S.S.L, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Spaziano v. Wainwright- FLSC, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - USSC, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Research Materials, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Death Warrant, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Research Material, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 18th Circuit FL- Motion to Vacate Judgement and Sentence Appendix Vol.III of III, ca. 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary -US DC FL, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Research Materials, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Dugger - FL Sc, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - USDC, FL ( 1 of 2), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - USDC, FL ( 2 of 2), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Research Materials, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Research Material - Franklin v. Duncan (1 of 3), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Research Material - Franklin v. Duncan (2 of 3), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Research Material - Franklin v. Duncan (3 of 3), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Research Materials- Repressed Memories ( 1 of 2), 1992-1995; Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Research Materials- Repressed Memories ( 2 of 2), 1992-1995; Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Radelet Affidavit, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Radelet and Bedau Affidavit, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Research Materials, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 1 of 4), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 2 of 4), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 3 of 4), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit- Record Experts ( 4 of 4), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit ( 1 of 2), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA, 11th Circuit ( 2 of 2), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary -U.S. D.C. FL., 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - Summary of Time Spent by Appointed Counsel, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Research Materials, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Research Materials - False Memory Syndrome Foundation, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit, Appendices ( 1 of 2), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit, Appendices ( 2 of 2), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC- Respondents Brief in Opposition to Writ of Ceritorari ( 1 of 2), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - Respondents Brief in Opposition to Writ of Ceritorari ( 2 of 2), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US CA 11th Circuit, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Singletary - US SC, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 April (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 June (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 June (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 July (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 August (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 September (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 October (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 November (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1995 December (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency- Application, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Before the Board of Executive Clemency- Supplemental Appendix, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Before the Governor and the Board of Executive Clemency, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence ( 1 of 3), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence ( 2 of 3), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence ( 3 of 3), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Information Packet- " The Hypnotized Witness and the Condemned Man: The Joseph ( "Crazy Joe") Spaziano Case", 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Interview- Anthony Frank Dilisio, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Research Materials, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Death Warrant, 1995 May (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Spaziano Execution Alert, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL SC (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL SC (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FL SL, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Request to Enforce Rights, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - USSL, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Statement to Governor Lawton Chiles in a Support of a New Trial, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 January (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 February (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 March (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 April (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 August (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings, 1996 December (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 9th Circuit, FL. (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 9th Circuit, FL. (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - 18th Circuit FL., 1996 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Florida v. Spaziano - FLSL, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Plea Bargain, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Draft Application for Story of Execution, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Newsclippings, Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Research Materials, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Draft Supplement to Rehearing Motions, Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - FLSC- Draft Amendment to Previously Filed Rehearing Motions, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Spaziano v. Florida - Trial Transcript, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Unlabeled Skeletal Photographs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Davidson James, 1970-1993; 2; 2.2
  This series contains legal material, notes, research files, and correspondence related to the trials of Davidson James.
  - Notes and Research, 1970; 1976; 1979; 1982-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Research, 1970; 1976; 1979; 1982-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - James v. Florida- FLSC, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Florida v. James- 13th Circuit, FL, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Florida v. James- 13th Circuit, FL ( 1 of 2), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Florida v. James- 13th Circuit, FL ( 2 of 2), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - James v. Wainwright- USSC, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - James v. Wainwright- Middle District of FL, Tampa Division ( 1 of 2), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - James v. Wainwright- Middle District of FL, Tampa Division ( 2 of 2), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - James v. Wainwright- USDC, M. FL, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit ( 1 of 3), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit ( 2 of 3), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit ( 3 of 3), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - James v. Wainwright - FLSC ( 1 of 3), ca. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - James v. Wainwright - FLSC ( 2 of 3), ca. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - James v. Wainwright - FLSC ( 2 of 3), ca. 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA 11th Circuit ( 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA 11th Circuit ( 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Re. James, 1988-1990; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA 11th Circuit, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - James v. Florida - FLSC, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - James v. Singletary - USCA, 11th Circuit, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - James v. Wainwright - USDC, M. FL, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - James v. Singletary - USDC, M. FL, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - James v. Singletary -USCA, 11th Circuit, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - James v. Singletary - USSC, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - James v. Dugger - USCA, 11th Circuit, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Bennie Demps, 1977-1990; 3; 1.8
  This series contains legal material and correspondence related to the trials of Bennie Demps.
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC ( 1 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC ( 2 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Demps-Presentence Investigation, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 1 of 4), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 2 of 4), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 3 of 4), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Demps v. Florida- District Court of Appeal, First District, FL ( 4 of 4), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Demps - Research, 1978; 1980; 1983-1988; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Demps v. Wainwright-USCA, 5th Circuit, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Demps v. Wainwright- USDC, M. FL, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Demps v. Florida- FLSC, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Demps v. Florida- US SC, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Demps - Death Warrants, 1982; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Demps - Psychological Evaluation [ Restricted], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Demps v. Florida- FL SC, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Demps v. Wainwright - USDC, M. FL, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Demps v. Wainwright- US SC, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Florida v. Demps - 10th Circuit, FL, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Demps v. Florida- FL SC, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Demps v. Wainwright- USDC, M. FL, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Demps v. Wainwright-USCA, 11th Circuit, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Demps v. Dugger- FLSC, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 1 of 4), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 2 of 4), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 3 of 4), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USDC, M. FL ( 4 of 4), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Demps v. Dugger-USSC, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Demps v. Wainwright-USCA, 11th Circuit, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Florida v. Demps - 8th Circuit, FL, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Demps v. Dugger- USCA, 11th Circuit ( 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Demps v. Dugger- USCA, 11th Circuit ( 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Demps- Affidavit, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)